Guide to the Seymour Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Parson - Dean Families, 1863-1949; Series VI; 3'9" (9 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Sarah (Seymour) Parsons: from Dean, Katharine (Parsons), 1886-1904 (Box 10, Folder 74-74a)
    - Sarah (Seymour) Parsons: from Dean, Katharine (Parsons), 1930-1931, undated (Box 10a, Folder 75)
    - Sarah (Seymour) Parsons: from Parsons, Robert Day, 1904-1915, undated (Box 10a, Folder 75a)
    - Sarah (Seymour) Parsons: from Parsons, William E., 1888-1916, undated (Box 10a, Folder 76)
    - Sarah (Seymour) Parsons: from Seymour, Charles (1843-1913), 1863-1912 (Box 10a, Folder 77)
    - Sarah (Seymour) Parsons: from Seymour, Elizabeth (Day), 1882-1908, undated (Box 10a, Folder 78)
    - Sarah (Seymour) Parsons: from Seymour, Sarah (Hitchcock), 1881-1913, undated (Box 10a, Folder 79)
    - Sarah (Seymour) Parsons: from Seymour, Thomas Day, 1865-1906, undated (Box 10a, Folder 80)
    - William Cheney Parsons: from A-Z, 1906, undated (Box 10a, Folder 80a)
    - William Cheney Parsons: from Dean, Katharine (Parsons), 1889-1913, undated (Box 10a, Folder 81)
    - William Cheney Parsons: from Parsons, Harriet Day, 1905-1906 (Box 10a, Folder 82)
    - William Cheney Parsons: from Seymour, Thomas Day, 1870-1902, undated (Box 10a, Folder 83-84)
    - William E. Parsons: from A-Z, 1909-1916, undated (Box 10a, Folder 84a)
    - William E. Parsons: from Dean, Lee Maltbie, 1933 (Box 10a, Folder 85)
    - William E. Parsons: from Parsons, Sarah (Seymour), [1914?], undated (Box 10a, Folder 86)
    - William E. Parsons: from Parsons, William Cheney, 1885 (Box 10a, Folder 87)
    - Louise (Parsons) Stanton: from Seymour, Elizabeth Atwater, 1945 (Box 10a, Folder 88)
    - Unidentified from unidentified, 1901, 1909, undated (Box 10a, Folder 89)
  - Writings
    - Katharine (Parsons) Dean: Book of Songs (Published), undated (Box 10a, Folder 90)
    - Katharine (Parsons) Dean: journal of trip to New York City, 1891 (Box 10a, Folder 91)
    - Katharine (Parsons) Dean: journal and notes of trip to Paris, undated (Box 10a, Folder 92)
    - Katharine (Parsons) Dean: reminiscence of Nathan Perkins Seymour, undated (Box 11, Folder 93)
    - Katharine (Parsons) Dean: recollections of travel, gardens, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - Katharine (Parsons) Dean: journal with miscellaneous notes on sermons, poetry, quotations, undated (Box 11, Folder 95)
    - Katharine (Parsons) Dean: research about "the mind and the body", 1919 (Box 11, Folder 96)
    - Katharine (Parsons) Dean: notes on the abdication of King Edward VIII, [1936-1937?] (Box 11, Folder 97)
    - Katharine (Parsons) Dean: notes and lists re: Miss Porter's School dramatic and choral productions, 1905-1919 (Box 11, Folder 98)
    - Katharine (Parsons) Dean: notes from Nathan Perkins Seymour's lectures, other notes about Spain, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 99)
    - Sarah (Seymour) Parsons: "Music on Our Journey", 1930 (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - William Chaney Parsons: notebook, 1874 (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Others
      - Sermons and religious poems [collected by Katharine P. Dean], 1918 (Box 11, Folder 102)
      - Miscellaneous notes re: travel, songs, quotations, sermons, art, poetry [collected by Katharine P. Dean], 1931-1932, undated (Box 11, Folder 103-104)
      - Prose and poetry quotations [collected by Katharine P. Dean], undated (Box 11, Folder 105)
      - Songs, poetry, quotations, prayers [collected by Katharine P. Dean], undated (Box 12, Folder 106)
      - Songs, poetry, quotations, prayers, addresses [collected by Katharine P. Dean], undated (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Printed Material
    - Magazine article: "With Good Queen Bess at Bryn Mawr" by Evangeline Andrews, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 108)
    - Magazine article: "Sarah Porter" by William M. Sloane, undated (Box 12, Folder 109)
    - Church programs, undated (Box 12, Folder 110)
    - Newspaper clippings re: abdication of Edward VIII, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 111)
    - Newspaper clippings re: food and recipes, 1934-1944 (Box 12, Folder 112)
    - Newspaper clippings re: World War II, 1936-1946 (Box 12, Folder 113)
    - Newspaper clippings re: miscellaneous, 1900-1945, undated (Box 12, Folder 114)
    - Pamphlets: religious literature, 1914-1945, undated (Box 12, Folder 115)
    - Pamphlet: tribute to Harley F. Roberts by Horace B. Taft, undated (Box 12, Folder 116)
    - Program: commemorative exercises at Yale, 1919 (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Programs: concerts and recitals at Miss Porter's School, 1900-1929 (Box 12, Folder 118-119)
    - Programs: plays, concerts in France, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 120)
    - Programs: miscellaneous concerts, 1902-1919, 1926, undated (Box 13, Folder 121)
    - Transcripts: Raymond Swing broadcasts, 1945-1946 (Box 13, Folder 122)
    - Exercise course, 1912-1913 (Box 13, Folder 123)
  - Personal and Memorabilia
    - Account, address books, 1893, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 124)
    - Wedding announcements, 1930, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - Garden Club: programs and newsletters, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 126)
    - Travel memorabilia, 1899, 1901, 1938, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 127)
    - Hawthorne Club: programs, notes, [1940?] (Box 13, Folder 128)
    - Palm print: Suzanne Stanton, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 129)
    - Receipts from trips abroad, 1900-1949 (Box 13, Folder 130)
    - Name plate: Lee Maltbie Dean, undated (Box 13, Folder 131)
    - Cards, 1906-1917, undated (Box 13, Folder 132)
    - Change purse, embroidered travel case, silk covered blotter, undated (Box 13, Folder 133)
    - Leather billfold and travelcase, undated (Box 13, Folder 134)
    - Miscellaneous, 1886-1946, undated (Box 13, Folder 135)
- Thomas Day Seymour, 1850-1909; Series VII; 7'6" (18 boxes)
  Thomas Day Seymour was born April 1, 1848, in Hudson, Ohio and spent his boyhood there. In 1864 at the age of sixteen, he worked for a few months on the Hartford Courant with his uncle, the editor, Thomas Mills Day. Responding to a notice in the Courant he, in January, 1865, joined the U.S. Christian Commission. Serving with this group dedicated to the preaching of religion and the teaching of reading to blacks in the U.S. Army, he witnessed the fall of Richmond in April. (See: MSS Group Number 619 for Confederate relics gathered by him.)
  Thomas Day Seymour returned to Hudson and attended Western Reserve College from 1866 until 1870, when he graduated first in his class. Having decided to devote his career to the classics, he went to Germany and for the next two years studied in Leipzig and Berlin. In the spring of 1872 he took the first of several trips to Greece. That autumn he returned to Hudson to take up the position of professor of Greek, a position he held until 1880 when he moved to New Haven to become Hillhouse Professor of Greek Language and Literature at Yale University.
  Thomas Day Seymour was a scholar of some reputation, a popular teacher, and an industrious administrator. A fine American Homeric scholar, he published many articles and several books. He served as an editor of the Classical Review and, beginning in 1903, as president of the Archaeological Institute of America. He was a founder of the American School at Athens and made numerous trips abroad to visit archaeological expeditions in Greece and the Middle East. His primary work, Life in the Homeric Age, was published just weeks before his death in 1907.
  In 1874 Thomas Day Seymour married Sarah Hitchcock, and they had three children: Elizabeth (Seymour) Angel, Clara (Seymour) St. John, and Charles Seymour (1885-1963).
  Correspondence consists of the letters addressed to Thomas Day Seymour alone or in conjunction with his wife and/or any of his children, from Seymour to non-family members and family members not represented in separate series, and letters to others from others which came into Seymour's possession. This section contains numerous letters from his wife, children, and parents. Sarah (Hitchcock) Seymour's letters, written when the couple was traveling separately, are rich in details of everyday life. The material is arranged alphabetically by sender in the first of the sub-sections, and by recipient in the latter two. Within each folder, the material is arranged chronologically.
  Writings is divided into the following sub-sections: Published; [Unpublished?], which contains material which may have been published but for which no evidence of publication could be found; and Unpublished, which is further divided by topic.
  Printed Material is arranged in chronological order.
  Personal and Memorabilia is arranged in chronological order.
  - Correspondence
    - Thomas Day Seymour from
      - A-G, Circa 1870-1907 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - H-N, Circa 1865-1907 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - O-Z, unidentified, Circa 1880-1907 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Allen, Frederic DeForest, 1880-1997, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Andrews, Catharine Augusta (Day), 1865-1994 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Andrews, Harriet Day, 1864-1985, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Angel, Elizabeth Day (Seymour), 1883-1907, undated (Box 14, Folder 7-14)
      - Blass, Frederick, 1891, [1906?] (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Bush, [underline], 1871 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Buss, Elle E., 1871 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Butcher, Samuel, 1904-1905 (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Coman, Martha Seymour
        See: box 1, folder 16
      - Day, Ellen P., 1865, 1885, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - Day, Thomas M., 1861-1903, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - Dean, Katharine (Parsons), 1885-1887, undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - D'Ooge, Martin, 1872 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - Egypt Exploration Fund, 1906-1907 (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - Ely, Mary (Day), 1880-1890 (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - Gibbs, Josiah Willard, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - Goodwin, W.W., 1886 (Box 15, Folder 26)
      - Greene, Jerome D., 1906 (Box 15, Folder 27)
      - Hitchcock, Clara Maria, 1871-1892 (Box 15, Folder 28)
      - Hunt, Samuel F., 1865-1868 (Box 15, Folder 29)
      - Jebb, Sir Richard, 1901, undated (Box 15, Folder 30)
      - Keep, Robert Porter, 1870, 1872 (Box 15, Folder 31)
      - Kellery, Mary B., 1871 (Box 15, Folder 32)
      - Kirby, William, 1865 (Box 15, Folder 33)
      - Lee, George, 1871 (Box 15, Folder 34)
      - Morley, Eliza Melissa (Hitchcock), 1872 (Box 15, Folder 35)
      - Morrill, Frank Forrest, 1871, 1907 (Box 15, Folder 36)
      - Norton, Charles Eliot, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 37)
      - Otis, Philo Adams, 1871 (Box 15, Folder 38)
      - Packard, Lewis R., 1880 (Box 15, Folder 39)
      - Parsons, Harriet, 1886 (Box 15, Folder 40)
      - Parsons, Sarah Day (Seymour), 1871-1905, undated (Box 15, Folder 41)
      - Parsons, William Cheney, 1867-1887 (Box 15, Folder 42)
      - Peabody, Annie Putnam, [1850?], undated (Box 15, Folder 43)
      - Perkins, William Rufus, 1871 (Box 15, Folder 44)
      - Perrin, Bernadette, 1885-1905 (Box 15, Folder 45)
      - Perry, E.D., 1907 (Box 15, Folder 46)
      - Putnam, Ellen Day, undated (Box 15, Folder 47)
      - Putnam, Katharine Day, 1872 (Box 15, Folder 48)
      - Roberts, W. Rhys, undated (Box 15, Folder 49)
      - Ryder, W.H., 1874 (Box 15, Folder 50)
      - St. John, Clara Hitchcock (Seymour), 1884-1903 (Box 15, Folder 51-54)
      - St. John, Clara Hitchcock (Seymour), 1905-1909, undated (Box 16, Folder 55)
      - Sandys, Sir John Edwin, 1900, 1905 (Box 16, Folder 56)
      - Schoenhof, [underline] and [underline] Moeller, undated (Box 16, Folder 57)
      - Seymour, Charles (1843-1913), 1862-1906 (Box 16, Folder 58-61)
      - Seymour, Charles (1885-1963), 1895-1902 (Box 16, Folder 62-67)
      - Seymour, Charles (1885-1963), 1902-1907, undated (Box 17, Folder 68-74)
      - Seymour, Elizabeth (Day), [1856?],1861-1889, undated (Box 17, Folder 75-77)
      - Seymour, Ella B., 1862 (Box 17, Folder 78)
      - Seymour, George Dudley
      - Seymour, Henry W.
      - Seymour, Joel M., 1865, 1871 (Box 17, Folder 79)
      - Seymour, Julia, 1865-1869 (Box 17, Folder 80)
      - Seymour, L.
      - Seymour, Nathan Perkins, 1862-1879 (Box 17, Folder 81-82)
      - Seymour, Nathan Perkins, 1880-1891, undated (Box 18, Folder 83-92)
      - Seymour, Sarah Melissa (Hitchcock), 1866-1874 (Box 18, Folder 93-96)
      - Seymour, Sarah Melissa (Hitchcock), 1874-1902, [1903?] (Box 19, Folder 97-110)
      - Seymour, Sarah Melissa (Hitchcock), [1903?], 1905-1907, undated, fragments (Box 20, Folder 111-116)
      - Sherman, John, 1870 (Box 20, Folder 117)
      - Smith, Charles Josiah, 1868 (Box 20, Folder 118)
      - Stevens, William Arnold, 1874 (Box 20, Folder 119)
      - Strong, George A., 1878 (Box 20, Folder 120)
      - Strong, Sidney, 1868 (Box 20, Folder 121)
      - Talcott, Mary Kingsbury, 1868-1880, 1895 (Box 20, Folder 122)
      - Terry, Milton S., 1898-1899 (Box 20, Folder 123)
      - Townsend, Timothy Dwight, 1886-1887 (Box 20, Folder 124)
      - Trimble, John, 1874 (Box 20, Folder 125)
      - Turning, E.H., 1874 (Box 20, Folder 126)
      - Weston, J.B., 1874 (Box 20, Folder 127)
      - White, Williams, 1886 (Box 20, Folder 128)
      - Whitney, William Dwight, 1873-1874, 1876 (Box 20, Folder 129)
      - Wilbur, Philo Adams, 1862-1870 (Box 20, Folder 130-132)
      - Williamson, James DeLong, 1871-1884 (Box 20, Folder 133)
      - Wright, Henry Burt, 1907 (Box 20, Folder 134)
      - Unidentified, 1871-1898, undated (Box 20, Folder 135)
    - Thomas Day Seymour to
      - A-Z, 1861, 1898, 1900, undated (Box 21, Folder 136)
      - Bonaparte, Ellen Charming (Day), 1905-1907, undated (Box 21, Folder 137-140)
      - Hewitt, Mr. [underline], 1902, undated (Box 21, Folder 141)
      - Knapp, William, 1894 (Box 21, Folder 142)
      - Mayor, J.B., 1883 (Box 21, Folder 143)
      - Otis, Philo Adams, 1866-1872, undated (Box 21, Folder 144-149)
      - Parker, Horatio, 1902 (Box 21, Folder 150)
      - Wilbur, Philo A., 1864, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 151)
      - Wright, John H., undated (Box 21, Folder 152)
      - Classmates at Western Reserve College, 1871, 1873 (Box 21, Folder 153)
      - "Aunt Nellie", undated (Box 21, Folder 154)
      - Unidentified, 1867, undated (Box 21, Folder 155)
    - Letters of introduction for Thomas Day Seymour, 1864-1865 (Box 21, Folder 156)
    - "Cousins" from Day, Alice H., 1892 (Box 21, Folder 157)
    - W.W. Goodwin from Kenyon, Sir F.G., 1906 (Box 21, Folder 158)
    - Nikey Stewart from Hawkins, George W., 1865 (Box 21, Folder 159)
    - L.C. Terry from Lord, W., 1831 (Box 21, Folder 160)
    - John H. Wright from Appleton, W.W., 1902 (Box 21, Folder 161)
    - John H. Wright from Goodell, Thomas D., 1901, 1903 (Box 21, Folder 162)
    - John H. Wright from West, Andrew T., 1901-1902 (Box 21, Folder 163)
    - John H. Wright from [Winians, S.R.?], 1899 (Box 21, Folder 164)
    - Portions of letters containing references to Alexander Metcalf Fisher [copy], undated (Box 21, Folder 165)
    - To unidentified from unidentified, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 166)
  - Writings
    - Published: books
      - Introduction to the Language and Verse of Homer, 1885 (Box 22, Folder 167)
      - Life in the Homeric Age: typescript, 1907 (Box 22, Folder 168)
      - Life in the Homeric Age: Ms, chapters 1-10 (Box 22, Folder 169-174)
      - Life in the Homeric Age Ms, chapters 11-17 (Box 23, Folder 175-180)
      - Life in the Homeric Age: typescript, final pages (Box 23, Folder 181)
      - Life in the Homeric Age: notes (Box 23, Folder 182)
    - Published: articles, 1862-1906, undated (Box 23, Folder 183-185)
    - [Unpublished?]: reports
      - Progress of Yale, undated (Box 24, Folder 186)
      - The Athenian School, undated (Box 24, Folder 187)
      - Committee on Entrance Examinations, undated (Box 24, Folder 188-189)
      - Entrance into Yale and Other Institutions of Higher Learning, 1901-1902 (Box 24, Folder 190)
    - [Unpublished?]: reviews and commentaries
      - On Book Reviewing, undated (Box 24, Folder 191)
      - On Aeschylus, undated (Box 24, Folder 192)
      - Frederick Blass, the works of, 1897 (Box 24, Folder 193)
      - Browning's Agamemnon, Preface to Studies, undated (Box 24, Folder 194)
      - E. Dawes The Pronunciation of Greek with Suggestions for a Reform in Teaching That Language, undated (Box 24, Folder 194a)
      - Franklin Dexter Biographical Sketches of the Graduates of Yale College, undated (Box 24, Folder 195)
    - Unpublished: diaries and notebook
      - Diaries, 1861-1863, 1865-1866 (Box 24, Folder 196-198)
      - Diaries, 1867-1894 (Box 25, Folder 199-200)
      - notebook, 1865-1867 (Box 25, Folder 201)
    - Unpublished: lectures and papers
      - Classical topics
        - Agamemnon, undated (Box 25, Folder 202)
        - Alexander, undated (Box 25, Folder 203)
        - "A Century of Classical Philology at Yale", undated (Box 25, Folder 204)
        - Christian obligation, undated (Box 25, Folder 205)
        - Classical archaeology, undated (Box 25, Folder 206)
        - [Communism in Greece], [1907] (Box 25, Folder 207)
        - "Crete, Greece, and Turkey", undated (Box 25, Folder 208)
        - Early Greek literature, undated (Box 25, Folder 209)
        - "The Greek Alphabet", 1883 (Box 25, Folder 210)
        - Greek plays, The passage of time in, undated (Box 25, Folder 211)
        - Greek poetry, undated (Box 25, Folder 212)
        - Harkness, Albert, undated (Box 25, Folder 213)
        - "Hesiod", undated (Box 25, Folder 214)
        - "Homer", undated (Box 26, Folder 215)
        - Homer: grammatical notes, undated (Box 26, Folder 216)
        - Homer: The Iliad, undated (Box 26, Folder 217)
        - Homer: notes and typescript fragment, undated (Box 26, Folder 218)
        - "Homeric Cosmology and Geography", undated (Box 26, Folder 219)
        - "Homeric Studies, Present Problems in", undated (Box 26, Folder 220)
        - Homeric verse, [1904?] (Box 26, Folder 221)
        - "Homeric Viands", undated (Box 26, Folder 222)
        - The Iliad and The Odyssey: The Homeric question, undated (Box 26, Folder 223)
        - Introduction to advanced study and teaching of Greek, undated (Box 26, Folder 224)
        - Latin prose exercises, 1862-1863 (Box 26, Folder 225)
        - A Learned Ministry, [1900?] (Box 26, Folder 226)
        - Legal relationships, undated (Box 26, Folder 227)
        - New Testament (Yale College course), undated (Box 26, Folder 228)
        - New light on ancient history, [1904?] (Box 26, Folder 229)
        - "Papyrus Manuscripts of Homer", undated (Box 26, Folder 230)
        - Philological seminary, undated (Box 26, Folder 231)
        - Philology, History of, undated (Box 26, Folder 232)
        - Pindar, Pythian IV, 1899 (Box 26, Folder 233)
        - Plato, Republic, undated (Box 26, Folder 234)
        - "Religion and Morality of the Greeks of the Homeric Age", 1897 (Box 26, Folder 235)
        - "Retrieved Greek Literature", [1907] (Box 26, Folder 236)
        - [Scanning Greek Verse], undated (Box 26, Folder 237)
        - "The Scientific Study of Greek Mythology", undated (Box 26, Folder 238)
        - "Slavery and Servitude in Homer", undated (Box 26, Folder 239)
        - [Theocritus], 1897 (Box 26, Folder 240)
        - "The Transmission of Ancient Books to the Present Time", 1892 (Box 26, Folder 241)
      - On Education
        - "The High School", 1898 (Box 27, Folder 242)
        - [The High Schools and the Colleges], 1899 (Box 27, Folder 243)
        - "Methods in Classroom Instruction", [1895] (Box 27, Folder 244)
        - "Oxford and Harvard Compared", [1895] (Box 27, Folder 245)
        - [The Position of Greek in the Educational System], [1906] (Box 27, Folder 246)
        - "The Study of Greek in Ohio Colleges", undated (Box 27, Folder 247)
        - "What is a Liberal Education?", 1900 (Box 27, Folder 248)
      - Travel
        - "On Asia Minor", 1904 (Box 27, Folder 249)
        - "A Midsummer Trip to the Land of Hellas", 1899 (Box 27, Folder 250)
        - "Modern Greece", undated (Box 27, Folder 251)
    - Unpublished: speeches
      - Address delivered to the annual meeting of the Western Reserve Alumni Association, [1907] (Box 27, Folder 252)
      - Remarks on the 20th anniversary of the American Philological Association, undated (Box 27, Folder 253)
    - Unpublished: notes
      - Miscellaneous notebooks, undated (Box 27, Folder 254)
      - notes written in the margins of Theodorus Bergk, ed. Aristophanis Ranae, 1881 (Box 27, Folder 255)
      - notes written in the margins of William Dindorf, ed. Homeri Ilias, undated (Box 28, Folder 256)
      - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 28, Folder 257)
    - Unpublished: miscellaneous
      - School compositions and orations, 1861-1870, undated (Box 28, Folder 258-259)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 28, Folder 260)
      - Miscellaneous copies of writings, undated (Box 28, Folder 261)
  - Printed Material
    - Children's primer and stories, 1885-1965, undated (Box 28, Folder 262)
    - Programs from Western Reserve College, 1862-1876, undated (Box 28, Folder 263)
    - Civil War pamphlets, 1861-1864, undated (Box 28, Folder 264)
    - Richmond Daily Dispatch, 1865 (Box 28, Folder 265)
    - Daily Richmond Whig
      See: box 114, folder 2
    - U.S. Christian Commission pamphlets, 1857-1865, undated (Box 29, Folder 266-272)
    - Religious pamphlets, 1857-1865, undated (Box 29, Folder 273-274)
    - German programs, 1871, 1903 (Box 29, Folder 275)
    - New Testament in Greek, 1881 (Box 30, Folder 276)
    - Programs in Greek, undated (Box 30, Folder 277)
    - Programs from the inauguration of Timothy Dwight as president of Yale, 1886 (Box 30, Folder 278)
    - Programs from the celebration of the 250th anniversary of the foundation of Harvard, 1886 (Box 30, Folder 279)
    - Program from the centennial celebration of Columbia College, 1887 (Box 30, Folder 280)
    - Yale commencement programs, 1891-1909 (Box 30, Folder 281-284)
    - Program from the inauguration of Arthur Twining Hadley as president of Yale
      See: box 104, folder 11
    - Programs from the Yale bicentennial celebration, 1901 (Box 30, Folder 285)
      See also: box 104, folder 12
    - Program from a performance of Hora Novissima, by Horatio Parker, performed by the Gounod Society of New Haven
      See: box 104, folder 13
    - Programs from the investiture of Lord Kelvin with the degree of doctor of laws, 1902 (Box 30, Folder 286)
    - Sixth catalogue of the Yale Divinity School Foreign Mission Library, 1902 (Box 30, Folder 287)
    - Proof sheets, 1902 (Box 30, Folder 288)
    - Yale baccalaureate address programs, 1903-1908 (Box 30, Folder 289)
    - Program from the commemoration of the 200th anniversary of the birth of Jonathan Edwards, 1903 (Box 30, Folder 290)
    - Yale Law School exercises program
      See: box 104, folder 14
    - Harvard University Gazette
      See: box 104, folder 15
    - Yale University Sunday service programs, 1907 (Box 31, Folder 291)
    - News clippings about Life in the Homeric Age, 1907-1908 (Box 31, Folder 292-293)
    - Obituaries, 1908 (Box 31, Folder 294)
    - Memorials, 1908 (Box 31, Folder 295)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31, Folder 296)
  - Personal and Miscellaneous
    - Civil War money, forms, certificates, piece of flag (Box 31, Folder 297)
    - Adelphion Society of Western Reserve College: constitution, minutes
      See: box 104, folder 16
    - Class record and account book, 1869, 1882, 1888-1889 (Box 31, Folder 298)
    - Certificates, diplomas
      See: box 104, folder 17 box 114, folder 3
    - Passports, 1870, 1872, 1898
      See: box 104, folder 18
    - Silliman House inventory (Box 31, Folder 298)
      See: box 104, folder 19
    - Test material from New Testament course, 1899 (Box 31, Folder 299)
    - Yale bicentennial invitations, tickets, 1901 (Box 31, Folder 300)
    - Invitations, 1901 (Box 31, Folder 301)